# **MATTEO CRISTIANO | CLOUD ENGINEER**

Via San Matteo 82G, 00015 Monterotondo (RM) | +39 349 2913958 | slb6113@gmail.com

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

I'm 31 years old, I'm graduate in "Astronomy and Astrophysic" - at the "La Sapienza" University of Rome - and I'm specialized on dynamics of dense stellar systems and exoplanets systems. I have been for about 2 years a PHP software developer (frontend, and backend), using the Laravel framework; every day, I also used the SQL language (MySQL databases), and managed the static analysis of the code through SonarQube. The projects in which I participated were built on AWS cloud, where I also managed release pipelines (in particular, using CodePipeline, and CodeBuild). In particular, I worked on the migration to AWS (with a serverless architecture, created by myself) of an entire ETL nightly process. I worked as System Administrator and Cloud Engineer, for the ConTe.it Customer team: in this role, I managed the servers and processes built on AWS cloud, from network/security topics to management of release pipelines (in particular, with the use of Jenkins), up to the creation/management of CI/CD processes. I also assumed the role of administrator of the company's WordPress applications. At the moment, I'm working as International Platform Operations Expert, at Lottomatica. In particular, I'm working as Cloud Engineer, for the Lottomatica Cloud team, in an international project, managing VMs, kubernetes clusters, and CI\CD processes built on AWS and Azure clouds. I am also interested in Machine Learning and Data Science topics/processes. I'm an extrovert guy, I like to work in team (more brains are better than one!), and I'm always ready to test and improve my own skills, overcoming my limits.

Ctrl - Create the roaring impossible

# **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- ✓ Cloud (AWS, Azure)
- ✓ CI\CD (Azure DevOps, Jenkins)
- Automation (Terraform. Ansbile, Packer, Puppet, Bash \ Powershell \ Python scripting)
- ✓ Documentation (Confluence)
- ✓ Agile
- ✓ Kubernetes (EKS, AKS, ArgoCD, Helm)
- ✓ Source control (Git, CodeCommit)

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Lottomatica SPA**

#### International Platform Operation Expert | 11 April, 2022 - Present

I'm working as Cloud Engineer, for the Lottomatica Cloud team, in an international project: in my role, I manage the servers and processes built on AWS and Azure clouds (using Terraform), from network/security topics to management of release pipelines (in particular, with the use of Azure DevOps), up to the creation/management of CI/CD processes. I manage creation and integration between different systems (Azure DevOps, ArgoCD, Kubernetes, Graphana, SonarQube, ..), servers life cycle (via Ansible processes), and Kubernetes cluster (on-prem, EKS, and AKS). [Ansible, CloudWatch/Events/Dashboard, CI/CD. Azure DevOps, Terraform, SonarQube, Network/Security, AWS, Azure, CentOS, Ubuntu, Windows, RedHat, Git, Bash/Python/Powershell scripting, Docker / Docker Compose, Kubernetes, EKS, AKS, ArgoCD, Confluence]

#### ConTe.it

# DevOps & Cloud Engineer | 01 April, 2020 - 10 April, 2022

I'm working as System Administrator and Cloud Engineer, for the ConTe.it Customer team: in my role, I manage the servers and processes built on AWS cloud, from network/security topics to management of release pipelines (in particular, with the use of Jenkins), up to the creation/management of CI/CD processes. Recently, I also assumed the role of administrator of the company's WordPress applications. I manage the integration between different systems (Graphana, SonarQube, Jenkins, ..), and the servers life cycle via Packer/Ansible processes. [Packer, Ansible, CodePipeline/CodeBuild, RDS/Aurora/MySQL/SQL Server, API Gateway/Lambda Functions, CloudWatch/Events/Dashboard, AWS Transfer Family/SFTP, CI/CD, Jenkins, SonarQube, WordPress Administration, Network/Security, AWS, CentOS, RedHat, Git/CodeCommit, Bash/Python scripting]

### IT Developer | 18 June, 2018 - 31 March, 2020

I'm a PHP software developer (frontend, and backend), using the Laravel framework (TDD & BDD methodology, code versioning using Git and CodeCommit); every day, I also used the SQL language (MySQL databases), and managed the static analysis of the code through SonarQube. The projects in which I participated were built on AWS cloud, where I also managed release pipelines (in particular, using CodePipeline, and CodeBuild). In particular, I worked on the migration to AWS (with a serverless architecture, created by myself) of an entire ETL nightly process. [PHP, SonarQube, SQL, MySQL, Unit/E2E test, Bash shell scripting, CodePipeline/CodeBuild, ETL, DataPipeline, RDS/Aurora, Git/CodeCommit, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Laravel, AWS]

#### **EDUCATION**

2015 - 2018 | La Sapienza University of Rome

Master of Astronomy and Astrophysics - 109/110